Today I would be talking about how to tack up a horse.
Now that the bridle is on, you want to make sure that it is fitted well.
You want to make sure that the bit is high enough, that there is 2-3 wrinkle in the corner of his mouth.
Right now there is non.
So tighten that up.
So now you can see that there is wrinkles in the corner of his mouth and it always important to put the pieces in the keepers.
Now adjusting the nose band, you want to make sure that the nose band goes underneath the cheek pieces.
It is just a little higher of the bit but just underneath his cheek bone there.
So I'm going to put that up a couple of holes once again tucking each piece under its keeper.
As you put the nose band on, the nose band should be snugged.
As we put the throat latch on, you still want to be able to fit about a fist right here.
It is important that you don't make this one too tight cause then when they go to flex, it can cut off some circulation.